We all have that one friend who is always late, don‘t we?
我们都有一个总是迟到的朋友，不是吗？
The one who turns up half an hour after the appointed coffee time.
她会在约定的喝咖啡时间过了整整半小时后才出现。
The person who is seemingly perpetually ‘stuck in traffic‘.
这个人似乎永远都“堵在路上”。
This dear friend will send a message saying “sorry, a bit delayed” when they’re already 20 minutes behind schedule.
这个亲爱的朋友会在已经比预定时间晚20分钟的时候发消息说“抱歉，有点耽搁了”。
I mean, what kind of friend is that?
我的意思是，这算哪门子朋友啊？
Or, if you‘re really honest, is that persistently tardy person actually you?
或者，如果你真的坦诚的话，这个一直迟到的人实际上就是你自己呢？
Either way, if you’re on the receiving end, lateness can be extremely irritating, even infuriating.
不管怎样，如果你是那个等待的人，迟到会极其令人恼火，甚至令人愤怒。
How on earth can people be so inconsiderate?
这些人到底怎么能如此不顾及别人呢？
Well, recent research suggests that there might be more to this than simple rudeness.
嗯，最近的研究表明，这件事可能不仅仅是无礼那么简单。
Psychologists from Washington University believe people perceive time differently.
华盛顿大学的心理学家们认为人们对时间的感知是不同的。
Their study gave participants a specific amount of time in which to complete a task, and even provided them with a clock.
他们的研究给参与者规定了完成一项任务的特定时间，甚至还给他们提供了一个时钟。
Despite this, some people became so engrossed in the activity that they completely lost track of time and forgot to check the clock.
尽管如此，有些人还是如此全神贯注于这项活动，以至于他们完全忘记了时间，也忘了看钟。
According to psychologist Dr Susan Krauss Whitborne, from University of Massachusetts Amherst, this is like when we scroll through our social media feed and think only five minutes have elapsed, when in fact twenty have slipped by.
根据马萨诸塞大学阿默斯特分校的心理学家苏珊·克劳斯·惠特伯恩博士的说法，这就好比我们浏览社交媒体的消息动态时，以为只过去了五分钟，而实际上不知不觉已经过去了二十分钟。
Does that feel familiar?
这种感觉熟悉吗？
She writes in Psychology Today that those who were better at clock-checking were therefore “less reliant on their potentially flawed internal timekeeper.”
她在《今日心理学》上写道，那些更善于看钟的人因此“更少依赖他们潜在有缺陷的内在时间感知机制”。
So, what about the reasons beyond our faulty inner clocks?
那么，除了我们有缺陷的内在时钟之外，还有哪些原因呢？
Well, our personality also plays a role.
嗯，我们的性格也起到一定作用。
Laura Clarke writes for BBC Capital that the less punctual among us often share traits such as “optimism, low levels of self-control, anxiety, or a penchant for thrill-seeking”.
劳拉·克拉克为BBC资本撰文称，我们当中不太准时的人往往有一些共同的特点，比如“乐观、自我控制能力低、焦虑，或者喜欢寻求刺激”。
Why optimism, you ask?
你可能会问，为什么是乐观呢？
Optimists tend to overestimate how much they can achieve and underestimate problems — which means they don‘t account for the long traffic jam on the way to meet you for that coffee.
乐观主义者往往会高估自己能完成的事情，低估问题——这意味着他们没有考虑到在来和你赴咖啡之约的路上会遇到长时间的交通堵塞。
Here’s another thought: maybe language is to blame?
还有另一个想法：也许该怪语言？
The English phrase ‘to be fashionably late‘ is used to describe the optimum time to arrive at an event.
英语短语“to be fashionably late”（时髦地迟到）被用来描述参加一个活动的最佳到达时间。
If you’re too early, you can appear overly eager, but if you‘re a bit late you seem cool and sophisticated.
如果你来得太早，你可能会显得过于急切，但如果你稍微晚一点，你似乎会显得很酷、很有品位。
The problem is, what one person regards as fashionably late, another may view as plain impolite.
问题是，一个人认为的时髦地迟到，另一个人可能会认为是完全不礼貌的。
So, next time you have coffee, do try to be on time.
所以，下次你去喝咖啡的时候，一定要尽量准时。